

Gaurav Daharia

I am open for Data Engineer / Analyst role(serving notice period LWD 12 march)

GET IN CONTACT

Mobile: +91-7973071348

Email: gauravdaharia80@gmail.com

PERSONAL DETAILS

• Total Experience 2 Years 8 Months

Current Location BengaluruDate of Birth Jun 05, 1999

Gender Male

Marital Status Single / Unmarried

SKILLS

- · Supervised Learning
- Tableau
- Aws
- Statistical Analysis
- Deep Learning
- Data Structures
- · Hypothesis Testing
- SQL
- Python
- Machine Learning
- Computer Vision

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Python
- ETL
- Machine Learning
- Statistical Data Analysis
- SQL
- Deep Learning
- · Product Analysis

LANGUAGES KNOWN

English

COURSES & CERTIFICATIONS

• Foundation In Machine Learning

PROFILE SUMMARY

I have over 2 years of experience working in data science,ETL tool. Currently, I work as Data Engineer, improving products and services for our customers by using advanced analytics, standing up ETL and analytics tools,creating and maintaining models, and onboarding compelling new data sets. Technologies: data science, machine learning, cloud computing, Python, ETL Tools, GCP, Deep Learning, AWS, Data Analysis using SQL, Exploratory Data Analysis, Statistical & probabilistic analysis.

EDUCATION HISTORY

Graduation

Course B.Tech/B.E.(Computers)

College Lovely Professional University (LPU)

Year of Passing 2021 Grade 7.05/10

Class XII

Board CBSE
Medium English
Year of Passing 2017
Grade 70-74.9%

Class X

Board CBSE
Medium English
Year of Passing 2015
Grade 80-84.9%

WORK EXPERIENCE

Jul 2023 to Present

Data Analyst at Amber

data-driven insights that fuel business growth: that's what I deliver as a results-oriented data analyst. With a deep understanding of statistical analysis, data visualization, and predictive modeling, I am skilled at extracting meaningful patterns from complex datasets. By translating data into actionable recommendations, I empower organizations to make informed decisions and seize opportunities. My expertise spans SQL, Python, R, and

SOCIAL LINKS

· www.linkedin.com/in/gaurav-daharia

Tableau, enabling me to uncover actionable insights and communicate them effectively to stakeholders. Let's connect to discuss how my analytical prowess and business acumen can help your organization harness the power of data for sustainable success. Technologies: data science, machine learning, cloud computing, Python, ETL Tools, GCP, Deep Learning Power BI.

Jun 2021 to Jul 2023

Data Engineer at Hexaware Technologies

I am a skilled Software Engineer with over 2 years of experience in ETL,Shell Scripting, SQL along with this I have experience in Data Analysis tools like Tableau & Excel. I have knowledge of popular Cloud Platform such as GCP,AWS and have working experience with Python & Machine Learning.

Jun 2021 to Jun 2021

Data Engineer at Hexaware Technologies

I am currently working as data engineer and currently working on ETL tools where our job is to setup batch load for loading tables. I have 1 year and 8 month of working experience in IT. Currently I have experience in working with technologies like gcp, shell script, python, hypothesis testing, feature engineering, SQL, Machine Learning.

PROJECTS

Customer Purchase Trend Analysis Using Python, 61 Days

This project was developed to do exploratory data analysis for one of the retail corporations. ?? I have used Central limit Theorem for customer purchase analysis where I have analyzed the customer category spending in how much range. ?? I have used python as well as Pandas and NumPy libraries for Central limit Theorem Application

Disease Detect, 730 Days

I have developed a web-based platform where user can share their disease symptom and get details about cure tips. ?? I have used Angular for frontend, Natural Language Processing for text preprocessing and FastAPI for serving text processing as service in frontend.